&gt;&gt; You might think of GPUs as devices built for
&gt;&gt; 皆さんが考えているとおり GPUはグラフィックを多用する
rendering graphically intensive video games, and that's true.
ビデオゲームをレンダリングするために構築されたデバイスです
But GPUs have also become extraordinarily important for deep learning.
しかしGPUはディープラーニングにおいても非常に重要です
GPUs are optimized for high throughput computation.
GPUはハイスループット計算に合わせて最適化されます
Whereas CPUs are mostly optimized for latency,
CPUは主にレイテンシーに合わせて最適化され
running a single thread of instructions as quickly as possible,
一連の命令をできるだけ速く実行しますが
GPUs are optimized for throughput,
GPUはスループットに合わせて最適化され
running as many simultaneous computations as possible.
できるだけ多くの同時計算を実行します
Throughput computing is important for computer graphics because we
コンピューターグラフィックスでは 画面上の多数のピクセルを同時に更新する必要があるため
want to update lots of pixels on the screen at the same time.
スループット計算が重要です
And it turns out that throughput computing is also important for
また ディープラーニングの基本となる計算には
deep learning because the computations
多くの並列処理が含まれるため
fundamental to deep learning have a lot of parallelism.
ディープラーニングにおいてもスループット計算は重要です
&gt;&gt; What level of acceleration do you typically see when you
&gt;&gt; CPUでのネットワークのトレーニングからGPUへ移行すると
move from training a network on a CPU to a GPU?
通常どの程度の加速が見られるでしょうか?
&gt;&gt; It depends on a lot of factors,
&gt;&gt; 実行しているソフトウェアの設計方法や
including how the software we're running has been designed,
比較しているCPUとGPUなど
and the precise CPU and GPU we're comparing.
さまざまな要因によって異なります
For example, the low power processor in your laptop
たとえば ノートPCの低消費電力のプロセッサーは
is going to be much slower than a big server processor.
大型のサーバーのプロセッサーよりはるかに低速です
But a rule of thumb would be that networks train
しかし経験則では ネットワークはCPUよりGPUの方が
about five times faster on a GPU than on a CPU.
約5倍速くトレーニングされます
&gt;&gt; That's similar to what I've seen,
&gt;&gt; 私も似たような経験があります
and I know from my own experience that it's just so much faster and easier
経験上 ネットワークのトレーニング速度が5倍から10倍に上がれば
to make progress when my network is training five or ten times faster,
はるかに短い時間で簡単に進歩させることができます
and I have all that extra time to experiment with
時間に余裕ができれば 新しいアプローチを試したり
new approaches and get fast feedback on how they work.
機能についてのフィードバックを より早く入手したりすることができます
Another good approach for getting fast feedback is to use transfer learning,
迅速なフィードバックを得るためには
to take advantage of networks that have already been
さらに 毎回ゼロから始めるのではなく
trained instead of just starting from scratch every time.
転移学習を使って トレーニング済みのネットワークを活用することをお勧めします